MITCHELL R. DORSEY

(513) 203-3344 -- Github: https://github.com/mitchdorsey

Email: mitchellrdorsey@gmail.com -- LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/mitchelldorsey/

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Developer searching for a role that allows me to use my adaptability and communication skills. Constantly broadening my skill set both technically and mentally. Past work experiences have given me strengths in thinking on my feet and continuously being flexible. Programmer that enjoys collaborating with a resourceful team.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Object Oriented Programming: C#, .NET, .NET Core, Java (Android framework)

Web Application Development: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, jQuery, MVC, MVVM, Bootstrap, XML (Android framework), Python, Blazor

Database Programming: SQL, table design and creation, stored procedures, views

Development tools and techniques: Entity Framework, Agile, Git, Visual Studio, Visual Studio Code, SSMS, MySQL Workbench, Android Studio, unit testing (MS Unit), integration testing, TDD, command line navigation

EDUCATION

Tech Elevator - Cincinnati, Ohio

September 2018 - December 2018

14-week .NET coding bootcamp learning database programming, .NET frameworks and design patterns, web application security, server side programming and client side web programming

TECHNICAL EXPERIENCE

Food World App

Web app deveoped in Blazor C#/.Net showcasing food that I have cooked or baked

Stock Market App

- Web app developed in C#/. Net Core using MVC pattern, Stock Market Web API, Javascript **Book Listing App** --- Android mobile app
- Developed in Java and XML, lists the published books on a given topic using the Google Books API Client Profile Ticket App
 - Developed in C#/.Net using MVVM pattern, Blazor, SQL, HTML, CSS, Javascript

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

VRI - Franklin, Ohio

March 2020 – August 2023

Software Engineer

- Created a C#/Selenium application automating a repetitive task, saving a manager up to 3 hours per week
- Performed or supported biweekly QA and production software releases through Jenkins
- Guided new developers through application changes that require using a third-party low code platform
- Performed code changes to client lookup application using C#/ASP.NET, C#/Blazor, SQL Server, and a third-party low code platform
- Added to team cohesiveness by building critical relationship through employee interactions

Physna - Cincinnati, Ohio

February 2019 - December 2019

Junior Software Developer

- Implemented features on C#/.Net Core web app and desktop client app with a MySQL database
- Coordinated with Application Engineer to evaluate and improve software
- Developed code fixes and enhancements for inclusion in future code releases and patches in C#/.Net Core
- Built desktop client installer file used for distribution using Visual Studio